The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
When Ling Tianhou returned from the Rain Celestial Realm,
he was followed by a Sword Spirit.
Where is that Sword Spirit ?
Speak !
The Seventh Purple Disciple
of the Heavenly Fate Sect !
You're Wang Lin !
This matter is a secret of our Da Lou Sword Sect.
Revealing it would certainly cost me my life.
Even if you are powerful,
the two of us have sword artifacts of the Dao Lou Sword Sect !
If we fight...
Speak
or die.
You've gone too far !
Da Lou Sword,
Heavenly Ghost Devour !
Death Finger !
He managed to break
Brother Lu's Heavenly Ghost Devour with a single finger !?
Die !
The Origin Soul leaves the body and merges with the life artifact ?
This spell is pretty interesting.
But the light of a firefly
can't be compared to the brightness of the moon !
A celestial sword !?
Mosquito Beast !
No !
Fellow cultivator Wang,
I'll tell you !
I'll tell you everything !
I can also give you a spell
that can use virgins to heal quickly.
You will definitely need it in the East Demon Spirit Sea !
And also,
this woman Qian Qin is still a virgin !
You can take her with you.
I beg you
to spare my life...
Where is the Sword Spirit
from back then ?
Back then, the Sword Saint fought the Sword Spirit
for 10 days and 10 nights.
In the end, the Sword Spirit lost to the Sword Saint.
Half of it was scattered into swords
and the remaining half
was sealed by the Sword Saint
in the Tide Abyss of the East Demon Spirit Sea.
Senior Zhou Yi's sword intent...
Since his Sword Spirit was torn in half,
some of his sword intent attached to ordinary swords.
Fellow cultivator,
can you let m...
A Life Seal...
I did it !
This metal element is very dense
but cannot be absorbed by the Heaven Defying Bead.
Eat up.
The treasure my sect searched for hundreds of years
was actually
fed to a beast ?
Once the Mosquito Beast emerges from the cocoon
it will definitely be several times stronger.
I was able to obtain this treasure because of you.
You can leave now.
Thank you, Senior !
3 months later
Earth Northern Demonic Lands
Planet Earth
I managed to condense 3 Life Seals.
Now I have a minor understanding of the Celestial Slaughter Art.
Senior Zhou Yi is my benefactor.
I must do my best to save him
in the East Demon Spirit Sea.
I also need to find more metal element treasures
to complete the Heaven Defying Bead.
Maybe it will also benefit Wan'er.
Greed,
what brings you here ?
Greed
Illusory Yin
I'm here
to present you with a heaven-sent opportunity.
With it, surpassing that old ghost the All-Seer
will be as easy as flipping your hand.
Oh ?
Tens of thousands of years ago,
the Cultivation Alliance announced that they'd reward
anyone who found a particular bead artifact.
The person who finds it
would receive a set of high-quality celestial spells.
Are the hidden injuries on you
related to that bead ?
Back then, in order to get it
we besieged the 2nd generation Suzaku.
I thought it would be very easy
but we did not expect
the opponent to be so formidable.
He managed to fight his way out.
Death Finger !
Since then,
there were no traces of him left.
Let's not mention the past,
my cultivation was insufficient.
But if the Sword Saint were to act,
you would've succeeded.
If you need, I can help you.
But before that
you must do something for me.
The East Demon Spirit Sea is about to open.
I want you to enter along with 12 of my disciples
to protect them
until they can complete the task I assigned them.
Xuan Yuan Sect
Planet Earth
Sun Yunshan
Young Master of the Xuan Yuan Sect
Early stage Soul Transformation
Brother Wang,
I am the Young Master of the Xuan Yuan Sect,
Sun Yunshan.
I was waiting for you.
Thank you for your trouble.
Brother Wang, please.
Sun Ruonan
Sun Yunshan's sister
Middle stage Soul Formation
I refuse !
You silly girl,
don't you know how dangerous that place is ?
If father didn't order me,
I wouldn't even want to go myself.
Brother Wang, please excuse us.
This is my younger sister Sun Ruonan.
This is
Senior All-Seer's disciple,
Wang Lin,
fellow cultivator Wang.
Hurry up and pay your respects !
Ruonan pays respects to Big Brother Wang.
Brother Sun, you just said you didn't want to go.
Why is that ?
Brother Wang, don't laugh at me.
The Demon Spirit Land
is a place filled with dangers and opportunities.
But I'm afraid it's a one-way trip...
East Demon Spirit Sea
Planet Tian Yun
Every 5000 years,
Tian Yun's East Demon Spirit Sea
will be swept away by a peculiar tidal force
that sucks abandoned artifacts from the all over the world
inside the East Demon Spirit Sea.
Over time,
that place
has become a veritable treasure trove.
Brother Zhang,
are you going in this time ?
I'm not going in.
But this spectacle only happens every 5000 years
so I came to see it.
I heard many powerful cultivators will come.
Yao Xixue
Blood Ancestor's daughter
Late stage Soul Transformation
This is the Blood Ancestor's daughter !
Her father Yao Xinghai
owns an entire planet !
His cultivation is heavenly !
It's rumored that
the Blood Ancestor passed all his techniques to Yao Xixue.
I heard he even defied the heavens to change her fate !
He's the All-Seer's new disciple !
He just entered the Heavenly Fate Sect
but was assigned by Senior All-Seer to go to the East Demon Spirit Sea.
He's truly remarkable...
There are so many people !
His cultivation is really ordinary
and there's nothing particularly outstanding about him.
Why did father tell me to pay special attention to him ?
The 12 Swords
of the Da Lou Sword Sect
The 12 Swords !
It's them !
We respectfully welcome Master.
Brother,
who is he ?
This is Senior Ling Tianhou.
Senior All-Seer
once invited Ling Tianhou and others
to enter and look for treasures.
The first 2 times, they returned safely.
But the third time,
only half of them came out.
Since then,
Ling Tianhou
parted ways with the All-Seer.
All these years,
they've been silent
about what happened inside.
They only said a single thing.
In the East Demon Spirit Sea,
there is an Ancient Demon.
From then on,
the East Demon Spirit Sea became a forbidden area.
Major sects take turns to guard it
since the treasures inside are too abundant to ignore.
Now,
it has become a trial ground for talented disciples.
The sects have already agreed beforehand
that disciples above Ascendant
cannot enter.
We pay respects to Senior All-Seer,
the master of Heavenly Fate.
Disciple Wang Lin,
pays respects to Master.
This event only happens every 5000 years.
You should watch carefully.
Within the tide,
you might glimpse at your heavenly fate.
Understood.
What ?
Do you know this child ?
I don't...
But he gives off a familiar feeling.
Maybe he's the descendent of an old friend ?
It's as powerful as the heaven's might !
It's starting !
Oh my god !
What kind of spells
are hidden inside the Demon Spirit Land ?
Artifacts,
mythical beasts,
legendary pills !
They're all treasures !
Heaven Metal Soil...
Exquisite Mix Liquid...
Ink Stone...
Ling Xi Horn...
They are all excellent materials from Tu Si's memory !
Old Man All-Seer,
could that be ?
This tidal force
can block Divine Sense !
Withdraw your Divine Sense !
This thing damages the Origin Soul,
it's not something Juniors can investigate.
Even those two are paying attention to what's inside...
Maybe this thing
is the true hidden treasure ?
It's
a token ?
For it to be this powerful,
the Demon Spirit Land
must hide an even greater secret.
Although this person's cultivation isn't high,
his Divine Sense still managed to enter the tidal wave.
He really mustn't be underestimated...
The East Demon Spirit Sea is open,
enter it now !
Take these rays of sword energy
as life saving artifacts for you 12.
You can go.
Just as you said,
in this tide
the last token we were waiting for finally appeared.
It's not what I said,
but what Heavenly Fate said.
Do we take it
or not ?
Back then, we suffered heavy losses.
If we want to obtain the token now,
we need to be prepared.
I think 200 years is enough,
then we'll enter the Demon Spirit Land together again
and retrieve the token.
In that case,
we'll meet again in 200 years.
My disciple Wang Lin
is a person of great fortune.
I just don't know
know how much fortune
he has left.
Not only have the character appearances been retconned but this flashback does not represent Situ Nan's defeat we see in episode 1.
This must be an earlier fight before that. The reason I'm thinking this is because Na Duo fought the Soul Refining Sect's Fourth Ancestor and was defeated by him so he cannot be present in the final fight against Situ Nan. Yes, I know I'm nitpicking...
I've been walking this path for endless years
just to catch a glimpse of your silhouette.
Is it the compass of fate
that wrote this outcome for us ?
The heavens want to erase your existence,
that's the obsession guiding me.
Is this the path to uncover
truths from falsehoods ?
In a world of murk and shadow,
only the flame of truth can light the way.
Look at them all,
being carried by the waves.
being drowned.
I don't want to believe in whoever decides fate,
I will let the world refine my soul.
So what if I become an Immortal and defy the heavens ?
I will fight.
I'll break through the abyss of despair
to finally learn who I really am.
My body is stained by the bloody color of slaughter,
I embrace this obsession.
I won't glance back at the wasteland I left behind.
Even if this suffering shatters my soul
and I'm reborn countless times in hell,
I'll still fight.
It's hard to avoid loneliness
when you are above everyone else.
Can a moth that has witnessed the flames of a Suzaku
be afraid of a firefly ?